[
    {
        "question": "Check out this video on Cassandra Tutorial for Beginners:",
        "answer": "Basic Interview Questions",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. Compare MongoDB with Cassandra.",
        "answer": "Criteria MongoDB Cassandra\nData Model Document Google Bigtable like\nDatabase scalability Read Write\nQuerying of data Multi-indexed Using Key or Scan",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What is Cassandra?",
        "answer": "Cassandra is one of the most favored NoSQL distributed database management systems by Apache. With its open-source technology, Cassandra is efficiently designed to store and manage large volumes of data without any failure. Highly scalable for Big Data models and originally designed by Facebook, Apache Cassandra is written in Java comprising flexible schemas. Apache Cassandra has no single point of failure. There are various types of NoSQL databases, and Cassandra is a hybrid of column-oriented and key–value store database. The keyspace is the outermost container for an application, and the table or column family in Cassandra is the keyspace entity.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. List the benefits of using Cassandra.",
        "answer": "Unlike traditional or any other database, Apache Cassandra delivers near real-time performance simplifying the work of Developers, Administrators, Data Analysts, and Software Engineers.\n Instead of master–slave architecture, Cassandra is established on a peer-to-peer architecture ensuring no failure.\n It also assures phenomenal flexibility as it allows the insertion of multiple nodes to any Cassandra cluster in any data center. Further, any client can forward its request to any server.\nCassandra facilitates extensible scalability and can be easily scaled up and scaled down as per the requirements. With a high throughput for read and write operations, this NoSQL application need not be restarted while scaling.\nCassandra is also revered for its strong data replication on nodes capability as it allows data storage at multiple locations enabling users to retrieve data from another location if one node fails. Users have the option to set up the number of replicas they want to create.\nShows brilliant performance when used for massive datasets and thus, the most preferable NoSQL DB by most organizations.\n Operates on column-oriented structure and thus, quickens and simplifies the process of slicing. Even data access and retrieval becomes more efficient with column-based data model.\nFurther, Apache Cassandra supports schema-free/schema-optional data model, which un-necessitate the purpose of showing all the columns required by your application.Find out how Cassandra Versus MongoDB can help you get ahead in your career!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Explain the concept of tunable consistency in Cassandra.",
        "answer": "Tunable consistency is a phenomenal character that makes Cassandra a favored database choice of Developers, Analysts, and Big data Architects. Consistency refers to the up-to-date and synchronized data rows on all their replicas. Cassandra’s tunable consistency allows users to select the consistency level best suited for their use cases. It supports two consistencies: eventual consistency and strong consistency.\nThe former guarantees consistency when no new updates are made on a given data item, i.e., all accesses return the last updated value eventually. Systems with eventual consistency are known to have achieved replica convergence.\nFor strong consistency, Cassandra supports the following condition:\nR + W > N where,\nN – Number of replicas\nW – Number of nodes that need to agree for a successful write\nR – Number of nodes that need to agree for a successful read",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. How does Cassandra write?",
        "answer": "Cassandra performs the write function by applying two commits: first, it writes to a commit log on the disk, and then it commits to an in-memory structure known as memtable. Once the two commits are successful, the write is achieved. Writes are written in the table structure as SSTables (sorted string tables). Cassandra offers faster write performance.\nGet 100% Hike!\nMaster Most in Demand Skills Now !\nBy providing your contact details, you agree to our Terms of Use & Privacy Policy",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Define the management tools in Cassandra.",
        "answer": "DataStax OpsCenter: It is the Internet-based management and monitoring solution for Cassandra cluster and DataStax. It is free to download and includes an additional edition of OpsCenter.\nSPM primarily administers Cassandra metrics and various OS and JVM metrics. Besides Cassandra, SPM also monitors Hadoop, Spark, Solr, Storm, ZooKeeper, and other Big Data platforms. The main features of SPM include correlation of events and metrics, distributed transaction tracing, creating real-time graphs with zooming, anomaly detection, and heartbeat alerting.\nKnow more about the management tools in Cassandra from this Cassandra Tutorial!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. Define memtable.",
        "answer": "Similar to a table, a memtable is the in-memory/write-back cache space consisting of the content in a key and column format. The data in a memtable is sorted by key, and each column family consists of a distinct memtable that retrieves column data via the key. It stores the writes until it is full, and then flushes them out.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What is SSTable? How is it different from other relational tables?",
        "answer": "SSTable expands to ‘Sorted String Table,’ which refers to an important data file in Cassandra and accepts regular written memtables. They are stored on disk and exist for each Cassandra table. Exhibiting immutability, SSTables do not allow any further addition and removal of data items once written. For each SSTable, Cassandra creates three separate files like partition index, partition summary, and a bloom filter.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Explain the concept of Bloom Filter.",
        "answer": "Associated with SSTable, Bloom filter is an off-heap (off the Java heap to native memory) data structure to check whether there is any data available in the SSTable before performing any I/O disk operation.\nLearn more about Apache Cassandra from the blog, Cassandra: The Buzzword in Database Management!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Explain CAP Theorem.",
        "answer": "With a strong requirement to scale systems when additional resources are needed, CAP Theorem plays a major role in maintaining the scaling strategy. It is an efficient way to handle scaling in distributed systems. Consistency, availability, and partition tolerance (CAP) theorem states that in distributed systems like Cassandra, users can enjoy only two out of these three characteristics.\nOne of them needs to be sacrificed. Consistency guarantees the return of most recent write for the client; availability returns a rational response within minimum time; and in partition tolerance, the system will continue its operations when network partitions occur. The two options available are AP and CP.\n\nIntermediate Interview Questions",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. State the differences between a node, a cluster, and a data center in Cassandra.",
        "answer": "There are various components of Cassandra. While a node is a single machine running Cassandra, cluster is a collection of nodes that have similar types of data grouped together. Data centers are useful components when serving customers in different geographical areas. You can group different nodes of a cluster into different data centers.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. How to write a query in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "Using CQL (Cassandra Query Language) we can write queries in Cassandra. Cqlsh is used for interacting with the database.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What OS does Cassandra support?",
        "answer": "Cassandra supports both Windows and Linux.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What is Cassandra Data Model?",
        "answer": "Cassandra data model consists of four main components:\nCluster: Made up of multiple nodes and keyspaces\nKeyspace: A namespace to group multiple column families, especially one per partition\nColumn: Consisting of a column name, value, and timestamp\nColumn Family: Multiple columns with the row key reference",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. What is CQL?",
        "answer": "CQL is Cassandra query language to access and query Apache distributed database. It consists of a CQL parser that incites all the implementation details to the server. The syntax of CQL is similar to SQL, but it does not alter the Cassandra data model.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. Explain the concept of compaction in Cassandra.",
        "answer": "Compaction refers to a maintenance process in Cassandra, in which the SSTables are reorganized for data optimization of data structures on the disk. The compaction process is useful during interacting with memtables. There are two types of compaction in Cassandra.\nMinor compaction: It gets started automatically when a new SSTable is created. Here, Cassandra condenses all the equally sized SSTables into one.\nMajor compaction: It is triggered manually using the nodetool. It compacts all SSTables of a column family into one.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. Does Cassandra support ACID transactions?",
        "answer": "Unlike relational databases, Cassandra does not support ACID transactions.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. Explain Cqlsh.",
        "answer": "Cqlsh expands to Cassandra Query Language Shell that configures the CQL interactive terminal. It is a Python-based command-line prompt used on Linux or Windows and executes CQL commands like ASSUME, CAPTURE, CONSISTENCY, COPY, DESCRIBE, and many others. With cqlsh, users can define a schema, insert data, and execute a query.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. What is Super Column in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "Cassandra Super Column is a unique element consisting of similar collections of data. They are actually key–value pairs with values as columns. It is a sorted array of columns, and they follow a hierarchy when in action: keystore > column family > super column > column data structure in JSON.\nSimilar to the row keys, super column data entries contain no independent values but are used to collect other columns. It is interesting to note that super column keys appearing in different rows do not necessarily match and will not ever.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. Define the consistency levels for read operations in Cassandra.",
        "answer": "ALL: Highly consistent. A write must be written to a commitlog and a memtable on all replica nodes in the cluster.\n EACH_QUORUM: A write must be written to a commitlog and a memtable on quorum of replica nodes in all data centers.\n LOCAL_QUORUM: A write must be written to a commitlog and a memtable on quorum of replica nodes in the same center.\nONE: A write must be written to a commitlog and a memtable of at least one replica node.\n TWO, Three: Same as One but with at least two and three replica nodes, respectively\nLOCAL_ONE: A write must be written for at least one replica node in the local data center.\nANY\nSERIAL: Linearizable consistency to prevent unconditional update\n LOCAL_SERIAL: Same as serial but restricted to a local data center\n\n\n\nAdvanced Interview Questions",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "21. What is the difference between Column and Super Column?",
        "answer": "Both elements work on the principle of tuples having name and value. However, the former’s value is a string, while the value of the latter is a map of columns with different data types.\nUnlike Columns, Super Columns do not contain the third component of timestamp.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "22. What is Column Family?",
        "answer": "As the name suggests, a column family refers to a structure having an infinite number of rows. Those are referred by a key–value pair, where the key is the name of the column and the value represents the column data. It is much similar to a hashmap in Java or a dictionary in Python. Rememeber, the rows are not limited to a predefined list of columns here. Also, the column family is absolutely flexible with one row having 100 columns while the other having only 2 columns.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "23. Define the use of the source command in Cassandra.",
        "answer": "Source command is used to execute a file consisting of CQL statements.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "24. What is Thrift?",
        "answer": "Thrift is a legacy RPC protocol or API unified with a code generation tool for CQL. The purpose of using Thrift in Cassandra is to facilitate access to the DB across the programming language.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "25. Explain Tombstone in Cassandra.",
        "answer": "Tombstone is a row marker indicating a column deletion. These marked columns are deleted during compaction. Tombstones are of great significance as Cassandra supports eventual consistency, where the data must respond before any successful operation.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "26. On what platforms does Cassandra run?",
        "answer": "Since Cassandra is a Java application, it can successfully run on any Java-driven platform or on Java Runtime Environment (JRE) or Java Virtual Machine (JVM). Cassandra also runs on Red Hat, CentOS, Debian, and Ubuntu Linux platforms.\nInterested in learning Cassandra? Enroll today in this Cassandra Training!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "27. Name the ports that Cassandra uses.",
        "answer": "The default settings state that Cassandra uses 7000 port for Cluster Management, 9160 for Thrift Clients, and 8080 for JMX. These are all TCP ports and can be edited in the configuration file: bin/cassandra.in.sh",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "28. Can you add or remove column families in a working cluster?",
        "answer": "Yes, but while doing that we need to keep in mind the following processes:\n Do not forget to clear the commitlog with ‘nodetool drain’\n Turn off Cassandra to ensure that there is no data left in the commitlog\n Delete the SSTable files for the removed CFs",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "29. What is replication factor in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "Replication factor is the measure of the number of data copies existing. It is important to increase the replication factor to log into the cluster.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "30. Can we change the replication factor on a live cluster?",
        "answer": "Yes, but it will require running repair to alter the replica count of the existing data.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Cassandra is a popular NOSQL database management system used to handle large amount of data. It is free and open source distributed database that provides high availability without any failure.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "2) In which language Cassandra is written?",
        "answer": "Cassandra is written in Java. It is originally designed by Facebook consisting of flexible schemas. It is highly scalable for big data.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "3) Who was the original author of Cassandra?",
        "answer": "The original authors of Cassandra are Avinash Lakshman and Prashant Malik. It was initially developed at Facebook to power the Facebook inbox search feature.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "4) Which query language is used in Cassandra database?",
        "answer": "Cassandra introduced its own Cassandra Query Language (CQL). CQL is a simple interface for accessing Cassandra, as an alternative to the traditional Structured Query Language (SQL).",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "5) What are the benefits/advantages of Cassandra?",
        "answer": "ADVERTISEMENT\nCassandra delivers real-time performance simplifying the work of Developers, Administrators, Data Analysts and Software Engineers.\nIt provides extensible scalability and can be easily scaled up and scaled down as per the requirements.\nData can be replicated to several nodes for fault-tolerance.\nBeing a distributed management system, there is no single point of failure.\nEvery node in a cluster contains different data and able to serve any request.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "6) Where Cassandra stores its data?",
        "answer": "Cassandra stores its data in the data dictionary.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "7) What was the design goal of Cassandra?",
        "answer": "The main design goal of Cassandra was to handle big data workloads across multiple nodes without a single point of failure.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "There are mainly 4 types of NoSQL databases:\nDocument store types ( MongoDB and CouchDB)\nKey-Value store types ( Redis and Volgemort)\nColumn store types ( Cassandra)\nGraph store types ( Neo4j and Giraph)",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "9) Mention some important components of Cassandra data models?",
        "answer": "These are some key components of Cassandra data model: -\nTable( collection of columns)\nNode\nCluster\nKeyspace",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "10) What are the other components of Cassandra?",
        "answer": "Some other components of Cassandra are:\nADVERTISEMENT\nNode\nData Center\nCommit log\nMem-table\nSSTable\nBloom Filter",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "11) What is keyspace in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "In Cassandra, a keyspace is a namespace that determines data replication on nodes. A cluster contains of one keyspace per node.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "12) What are the different composite keys in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "In Cassandra, composite keys are used to define key or a column name with a concatenation of data of different type. There are two types of Composite key in Cassandra:\nRow Key\nColumn Name",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "13) What is data replication in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "Data replication is an electronic copying of data from a database in one computer or server to a database in another so that all users can share the same level of information. Cassandra stores replicas on multiple nodes to ensure reliability and fault tolerance. The replication strategy decides the nodes where replicas are placed.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "14) What is node in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "In Cassandra, node is a place where data is stored.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "15) 15) What do you mean by data center in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "Data center is a complete data of clusters.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "16) What do you mean by commit log in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "In Cassandra, commit log is a crash-recovery mechanism. Every write operation is written to the commit log.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "17) 17) What do you mean by column family in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "Column family is a table in RDMS that contains an ordered collection of rows.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "18) What do you mean by consistency in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "Consistency in Cassandra specifies how to synchronize and up to date a row of Cassandra data and its replicas.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "19) How many types of tunable consistency are supported in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "It supports two consistencies: Eventual Consistency and Strong Consistency.\nThe eventual consistency is used when no new updates are made on a given data item, all accesses return the last updated value eventually. Systems with eventual consistency are known to have achieved replica convergence.\nCassandra supports the following conditions for strong consistency:\nR + W > N\n\nHere\nN: Number of replicas\nW: Number of nodes that need to agree for a successful write\nR: Number of nodes that need to agree for a successful read",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "20) What is tunable consistency in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "Tunable Consistency is a phenomenal characteristic of Cassandra which makes it a popular choice. Consistency refers to the up-to-date and synchronized data rows on all their replicas. Cassandra's Tunable Consistency facilitates users to select the consistency level best suited for their use cases.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "21) What is the syntax to create keyspace in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "CREATE KEYSPACE <identifier> WITH <properties>",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "22) What is a column family in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "In Cassandra, a collection of rows is referred as \"column family\".",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "23) How does Cassandra perform write function?",
        "answer": "Cassandra performs the write function by applying two commits:\nFirst commit is applied on disk and then second commit to an in-memory structure known as memtable.\nWhen the both commits are applied successfully, the write is achieved.\nWrites are written in the table structure as SSTable (sorted string table).",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "24) What is memtable?",
        "answer": "Memtable is in-memory/write-back cache space containing content in key and column format. In memtable, data is sorted by key, and each ColumnFamily has a distinct memtable that retrieves column data via key. It stores the writes until it is full, and then flushed out.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "25) What is SSTable?",
        "answer": "SSTable is a short form of 'Sorted String Table'. It refers to an important data file in Cassandra and accepts regular written memtables. They are stored on disk and exist for each Cassandra table.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "26) How the SSTable is different from other relational tables?",
        "answer": "SStables do not allow any further addition and removal of data items once written. For each SSTable, Cassandra creates three separate files like partition index, partition summary and a bloom filter.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "27) What are the management tools in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "DataStaxOpsCenter: It is an internet-based management and monitoring solution for Cassandra cluster and DataStax. It is free to download and includes an additional Edition of OpsCenter.\nSPM: SPM primarily administers Cassandra metrics and various OS and JVM metrics. It also monitors Hadoop, Spark, Solr, Storm, zookeeper and other Big Data platforms besides Cassandra.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "28) Mention some important features of SPM in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "The main features of SPM are:\nCorrelation of events and metrics\nDistributed transaction tracing\nCreating real-time graphs with zooming\nDetection and heartbeat alerting",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "29) What is cluster in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "In Cassandra, the cluster is an outermost container for keyspaces that arranges the nodes in a ring format and assigns data to them. These nodes have a replica which takes charge in case of data handling failure.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "30) What is the role of ALTER KEYSPACE?",
        "answer": "ALTER KEYSPACE is used to change the value of DURABLE_WRITES with its related properties.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "31) What do you mean by Cassandra-Cqlsh?",
        "answer": "Cqlsh is a Cassandra query language shell used to execute the commands of CQL (Cassandra query language).",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "32) What are the differences between a node, a cluster, and datacenter in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "Node: A node is a single machine running Cassandra.\nCluster: A cluster is a collection of nodes that contains similar types of data together.\nDatacenter: A datacenter is a useful component when serving customers in different geographical areas. Different nodes of a cluster can be grouped into different data centers.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "33) What is the use of Cassandra CQL collection?",
        "answer": "Cassandra CQL collection is used to collect the data and store it in a column where each collection represents the same type of data. CQL consist of three types of types:\nSET: It is a collection of unordered list of unique elements.\nList: It is a collection of elements arranged in an order and can contain duplicate values.\nMAP: It is a collection of unique elements in a form of key-value pair.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "34) What is the use of Bloom Filter in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "On a request of a data, before doing any disk I/O Bloom filter checks whether the requested data exist in the row of SSTable.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "35) How does Cassandra delete data?",
        "answer": "In Cassandra, to delete a row, it is required to associate the value of column to Tombstone (where Tombstone is a special value).",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "36) What is SuperColumn in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "In Cassandra, SuperColumn is a unique element containing similar collection of data. They are actually key-value pairs with values as columns.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "37) What is the difference between Column and SuperColumn?",
        "answer": "Difference between Column and SuperColumn:\nThe values in columns are string while the values in SuperColumn are Map of Columns with different data types.\nUnlike Columns, Super Columns do not contain the third component of timestamp.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Hadoop, HBase, Hive and Cassandra all are Apache products.\nApache Hadoop supports file storage, grid compute processing via Map reduce. Apache Hive is a SQL like interface on the top of Haddop. Apache HBase follows column family storage built like Big Table. Apache Cassandra also follows column family storage built like Big Table with Dynamo topology and consistency.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "39) What is the usage of \"void close()\" method?",
        "answer": "In Cassandra, the void close() method is used to close the current session instance.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "40) Which command is used to start the cqlsh prompt?",
        "answer": "The cqlsh command is used to start the cqlsh prompt.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "41) What is the usage of \"cqlsh-version\" command?",
        "answer": "The \"cqlsh-version\" command is used to provide the version of the cqlsh you are using.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "42) Does Cassandra work on Windows?",
        "answer": "Yes. Cassandra is compatible on Windows and works pretty well. Now its Linux and Window compatible version are available.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "43) What is Kundera in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "In Cassandra, Kundera is an object-relational mapping (ORM) implementation which is written using Java annotations.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "44) What do you mean by Thrift in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "Thrift is the name of RPC client which is used to communicate with the Cassandra Server.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    },
    {
        "question": "45) What is Hector in Cassandra?",
        "answer": "Hector was one of the early Cassandra clients. It is an open source project written in Java using the MIT license.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "cassandra"
    }
]